There's a world on both sides of the rainbow where songs come true
and every time it rains, it rains Pennies from Heaven.
Pennies from Heaven is a drama, music, romance film directed by Herbert Ross.
During the Great Depression, a sheet music salesman seeks to escape his dreary life
through popular music and a love affair with an innocent schoolteacher.
Arthur, played by Steve Martin.
Eileen, played by Bernadette Peters.
Joan, played by Jessica Harper.
The Accordion Man, played by Vernel Bagneris.
Mr. Warner, played by John McMartin.
The Detective, played by John Karlen.
Pennies from Heaven is a 1981 American musical romantic drama film directed
by Herbert Ross, based on the 1978 BBC television drama.
Dennis Potter adapted his screenplay from the BBC series for American audiences, changing its
setting from London and the Forest of Dean to Depression-era Chicago and rural Illinois.
The film stars Steve Martin, Bernadette Peters,
Christopher Walken and Jessica Harper.
Choreographed by Danny Daniels, the film includes musical numbers consisting of actors lip-syncing and dancing to popular songs of the
1920s–30s, such as "Let's Misbehave", "Life Is Just a Bowl of Cherries", "Let's Face the Music and Dance" and the title song.
While positively received by critics, it was a box office
bomb, grossing just a fraction of its budget.
It received 3 nominations at the 54th Academy
Awards, but didn't win any of them.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois,
marriage, musical, great depression, teacher.
The tone is emotional.